# LEIF HUHN

Chicago, IL 60660 leif.n.huhn@gmail.com (415) 583-5685

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Site-reliability engineer with over 18 years of experience in IT. Experience in a wide variety of technologies and platforms. Particular strengths in maintaining Linux servers and automating processes using Salt and Python scripting. Initiated infrastructure improvements as well as new programming methodologies and systems. Motivated self-starter and enthusiastic team member.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# CenturyLink Cloud

2015 - Present

Senior Lead Software Developer

Bellevue, WA and St. Louis, MO

- · Managed cloud services in both AWS and CenturyLink cloud.
- · Used SaltStack to manage Linux, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, and Elastic Search.
- · Deployed Master-Master replication in order to perform blue-green upgrade deployment of critical database infrastructure.
- · Deployed Consul in multi-datacenter mesh in order to support application failover.
- · Used Bash and Go scripting for various system administration purposes.
- · Created a virtual firewall product for CenturyLink's cloud using NSX Edge firewalling.
- · Migrated features from a monolithic control portal to microservices running on Kubernetes.

#### Riverbed Technology

2010 - 2015

Team Lead

San Francisco, CA

- · Mentored junior coders.
- · Oversaw maintenance of critical pieces of our testing infrastructure.
- · Conceived of, collaboratively designed, and oversaw development of an automated program "Rack-and-Roll," greatly simplifying the process of adding new hardware into the lab.
- · Created system to power down unused testing machines, saving power, cooling, and money.
- · Automated VMWare vCenter to automate the installation and testing of VMs.
- · Troubleshot various DHCP, TFTP, and PXE networking problems using Cisco, Force10 hardware.
- · Troubleshot problems with internal appliance manufacturing, including bugs in the unreleased product, bugs in the build system, hardware problems, user error, networking problems, service outages, etc.
- · Used puppet to automate system administration tasks.
- · Refactored testing codebase for greater maintainability.
- · Made OO design decisions for future direction of testing codebase.

## Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

2003 - 2010

System Administrator

Berkeley, CA

- · Installed, maintained, and updated Linux and Windows servers providing critical infrastructure (mail, web, dns, nfs, mysql, iptables, RAID, LVM, and ssh).
- · Reduced our server footprint by 60% by migrating applications from legacy versions of BSD and SunOS to Linux, thereby saving on licensing costs.

- · Managed remote servers for multiple law firms. Worked with system administrators from client companies to resolve networking problems.
- · Transitioned our systems to 64-bit to allow processing of larger datasets.
- · Evaluated server workloads and made purchasing decisions.
- · Hired and oversaw contractors to upgrade data and phone wiring.
- · Used Nagios to provide 24/7/365 monitoring of critical services.
- · Responsible for migrating data obtained through legal discovery into our systems (i.e. from Oracle, PostreSQL, etc).
- · Automated backup processes.

# Drogin, Kakigi & Associates

Web Developer

2001 - 2003Berkeley, CA

- $\cdot$  Developed Model-View-Controller web framework with a MySQL backend tailored for the specific needs of the company.
- · Created websites to allow hundreds of paralegals from around the country to work together to interview thousands of plaintiffs in large class action lawsuits.
- · Oversaw and trained junior web developers.
- · Wrote Perl programs to process data in legacy formats.

# Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission

Web Developer

1999 - 2000 Tallahassee, FL

- · Developed data aware client side web applications.
- · Increased productivity through the creation of a system for dynamically tracking bird migration patterns thereby freeing an analyst from writing weekly reports.
- · Managed IIS web servers.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Perl, Python, C/C++, Java, Go.
- · XML, HTML, SQL, CGI
- · NoSQL databases, Hadoop, HBase, Zookeeper, Kafka, Consul, Couchbase
- · RabbitMQ, Redis
- · Apache, IIS
- · MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, SQL Server
- · Cisco IOS, Force10 FTOS
- · Puppet, Salt, Linux, BSD, Solaris
- · Sendmail, DNS
- · Icinga, Nagios, Snort, Kibana, Graphite, Carbon

- · RAID, LVM, NFS
- · tcpdump, wireshark
- · Unix Scripting: bash, tcsh, expect
- · Windows Deployment, Hyper-V, cygwin, Power-shell
- · OS X
- · VMWare ESX, VMWare NSX, vCenter, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, KVM
- · LATEX

#### **EDUCATION & HOBBIES**

- · University of California, Berkeley, CA Bachelors Degree in Physics
- · Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL
  - Completed University Honors Program. GPA: 3.9
- · Conversational in American Sign Language, some knowledge of Spanish, French, and Japanese